Okay, now we're going to learn another very powerful method to split
好的 现在我们将会学习另外一种非常强大的方法
points in the plane.
来分开平面上的点
So let's say we have thee four points arranged like this and
那么加入我们有三四个点像这样排列
we want to split them.
我们想要分开他们
It seems again that a line won't do the job
似乎一条线又不能完成这个任务
since they're already over the line and the red ones are on the sides.
因为他们已经在一条线上面 这些红色的点在边上
So we need to think outside the box.
所以我们需要跳出这个思维方式
One way to think out of the box is to use a curve like this to split them.
一个跳出思维定势的方式是用一个这样的曲线来分开他们
Another one is to actually think outside the plane.
另外方式事实上是在平面外面考虑
And think of the points as lying in three dimensional space.
想像一下这些点正在一个三维的空间中
Here are the four points over the plane.
有4个点在平面上面
We add an extra axis, the z axis for the third dimension.
对于第三个维度 我们增加一个额外的轴 z轴
And if we can find a way to lift the two green points,
如果我们能够找到一个方式来提升这两个绿色的点
then we'd be able to separate them with a plane.
那么我们就能够用平面分开他们
So what seems like the better solution, to think within the plane and
那么哪一个似乎是一个更好的解决办法 在一个平面里想着
separate the points with a curve?
有一条曲线分开这些点
Or to think of the points in space, and separate them with a plane?
或者是想着在空间里面用平面分开他们？
Well, it turns out that these two are actually the same method.
表明这两个其实是同样的办法
Don't worry if it seems confusing, we'll see it in more detail later.
如果听起来有点疑惑 别担心 我们随后会看更多的细节
This method is called the Kernel Trick, and
这种办法被称为核方法
it's very well used in support vector machines.
在支持向量机中它被很好的使用
Okay, so let's study one of them in more detail, let's study the curve trick.
好的 让我们学习其中的一个更多的细节 让我们先来学习曲线的办法
First, let's start by putting coordinates on the points.
首先让我们开始把坐标放在点上
So this one is (0,3).
那么这个是(0,3)
This one is (1,2).
这个是 (1,2)
This one is (2,1).
这个是 (2,1)
And this one is (3,0).
这个是(3,0)
And what we need is a way to separate the green points from the red points.
我们需要的是一种办法从红色的点中分出绿色的点
So if the points coordinates are (x,y), maybe we need an equation
那么如果点的坐标是 (x,y) 也许我们需要一个方程
on the variables x and y that gives us large values for
变量是 x 和 y 对于绿色的点
the green points and small values for the red points, or vice versa.
给我们一个大的值 对于红色的点给我们一个小的值 或者是相反的情况
So which of the following equations could come to our rescue?
那么下面那个方程能够解决这个问题呢？
The sum of the two coordinates x + y, the product of the coordinates,
两个坐标的求和 x + y 坐标乘积 xy
xy or the first coordinates squared, x squared.
或者是第一个坐标的平方 x 平方
Submit your answer below.
在下面提交你的答案